Elsie Clews Parsons Papers 1835-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.29
American Philosophical Society
- Elsie Clews Parsons Papers II, 1898-1937
  - Series II. Personal Correspondence, 1882-1941; 1965
    - Patterson, Rufus L., 1931; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Perla, Doris, 1885-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Potomac School, 1909-10 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Potter, Dorothea, 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Prentice[?], Ezra, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Putnam, Ruth, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Redman, Rose, 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Remsen, Robert G., 1887? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Reynolds, George P., 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Richman, Julia, 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Robbins, A.M., 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Robbins, Harry Pelham, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Robinson, Kenneth, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Rogers, Janet Pierpont, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Roony, Henry F., 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Rose, Antonio, 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Roosevelt, Alice Lee, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Rosenblatt, Herman P., 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Ruel, [?], 1888 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Ruhl, Anna, 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Russell, Jane, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Rye Country Club (N.Y.), 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Salem, Clara R., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Schaefer, Kathryn C., 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Seaman, Stanley M., 1914? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Sedgwick, Alexander, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Seton, G.G., 1908? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Silva, Gregory T., 1917-19 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Silva, Pennie, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Smadbeck, Warren, 1928 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Smith, James G., 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Smith, Margaret A. Stewart, 1916; 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Smith, P.C., 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Station Master (Great Barrington), 1915? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Stebbins, Mary, 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Stewart, Lispenard, 1888 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Stickney, C.L., 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - F.W. Stillman Company, 1930; 1941 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Stillman Co.
    - Stokes, Mr., 1884 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Strang, Louisa L., 1894 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Sullivan, Mark, 1908? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Swift, George Montague, 1905-09? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Sylvester, Richard, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Tanenbaum, Florence Lucy, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Thompson, Frank E., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Tiffany & Co. Safe Deposit Dept., 1916; 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Todd, R.H., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Torrell, Carlotta Russell, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Townsend, Amy, 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Trevore, Emily H., 1890 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Tusserand, [?], 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Unidentified (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #1, 1883-1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #2, 1908-10 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #3, 1911-13 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #4, 1914-19 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #5, 1920-36 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #6, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #7, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Folder #8, 1885-1933; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
        written by ECP
    - Vaillant, Abby A., 1888-89 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Van Hoorde, Raoul, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Vatable, Jules J., 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Ward, Mary A., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Washington (D.C.). Office of the Engineer Commissioner of the District of Columbia, 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Watson, John M., 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Westervelt, Florence, 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Wickersham[?], Neil, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Wild, S.E., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Williams, L.W., 1884 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Winters, John D., 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Winthrop, Bronson, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Woely, M.H., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Worthington, Edward Stanley, 1885; 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      uncle
    - Young, J.H., 1910-11 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
      - Parsons, Elsie (Lissa) (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
    - Zuni, Flora, 1924 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 11)
  - Series III. Lectures and Manuscripts, 1898-1947
    contains Parsons' addresses, lectures, and manuscripts. Notes or drafts that can be identified have been placed in this series. Unidentifiable notes or drafts have been placed in Series IV as "Miscellaneous." Correspondence with publishers, critiques from colleagues, and printed reviews have been placed in this series by manuscript title. Arrangement is alphabetical by type of material (e.g. Address, Manuscript), and within each type alphabetical by title. There is a bibliographic card file kept by Parsons from 1914 to 1920, listing articles sent to publishers with notes made on rejections and acceptances. Some items are from Parsons' graduate coursework at Columbia University. Subjects include all of Parsons' interests: anthropology of the Southwest, sociology, feminism, pacifism, and folklore, in addition to a few fictional works. Unpublished manuscripts include: "In the Southwest," "The Imaginary Mistress," "Journal of a Feminist," and "Journal of a Pacifist."
    - Addresses (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Addresses - "Cultural Uniformity", 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Addresses - Higher Education of Women and The Family, 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Addresses - [On Mitla, Oaxaca], 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Addresses - "Remarks at Sanger dinner", 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
        General note
        (end of Addresses)
    - Anthropology game, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Articles about or referring to ECP, 1915-36 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Articles by ECP, 1905-06; 1915-17; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Bibliography, 1914-20 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Bibliography of Southwest Mythology, [1927?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Lectures (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - "Folk-Lore at Home", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - Lecture notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - Remarks to Prof. Boas' class in anthropology, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - "The Social Conventions", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - "Spanish Folk Culture in America", 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Lectures - "The Value of Folk Ethics", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
        (end of Lectures)
    - Letters to Editors, 1917-18; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
    - Manuscripts (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - "Adivinanzas de Mexico, D.F.", 1932? (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - "Afternoon Tea", [ca. 1912?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
        skit
      - Manuscripts - "The Antagonism of the Private to the Public School System", [ca. 1905] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - [Arab Folk Tales], n.d.; 15 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - "Arabic Elements in Negro Folk Tales", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - "An Automobile Demonstrator, His Mother, and Old Joe Washington", 1924 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "The Aversion to Anomalies", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Avoidance in Custom and in Ceremonialism" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - Bibliography, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        work unknown skit
      - Manuscripts - "The Board of Trustees", [1913?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "The Canes", [ca. 1932] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Carnival at Zaachila", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "The Case for Cross-Cousin Marriage among Pueblo Indians", 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Ceremonial Defloration", [1917] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Ceremonial Reluctance", n.d.; 9 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Christian Rites in Zuni Ceremonialism", [1918?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Christian Rites in Zuni Ceremonialism" - Correspondence, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        - Spier, Leslie (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Class Lines in 1914-15", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Conventionality", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "The Criminal", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Cultural Change among Spanish Indians" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Decorative Scenery", [1915?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "A Derelict of Progress", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Discomfiture and Evil Spirits", [1915] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Discussion of Prof. Weatherly's Paper", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Dual Organization", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Eden or Athens", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "The End of Gerontocracy: a Warning to the middle-Aged" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Engagements", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Escape Up the Tree", 1919; [1922] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        - Swanton, John R. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Ethnology in a Liberal Education", [1914?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - The Family - Correspondence (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        - Folder #1, 1905-Nov. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        - Folder #2, Dec. 1906-1911 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - The Family - Reviews, 1907; 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - Fear and Conventionality - Correspondence, 1914-15 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - Fear and Conventionality - Reviews, 1914-20 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Feminism and Men" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Die Flucht auf den Baum" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        English translation
        -See Ser.III, Mss. - "Escape Up the Tree"
      - Manuscripts - "Folklore from Dacca District, Bengal", [ca.1923] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
        -For related materials, see Ser.IV, Hindu (Bose) - Notebooks #1-3, 1923; and Ser.IV, Hindu - Notes, [1923]
      - Manuscripts - "Folk Lore from Georgia", [1934?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 2)
      - Manuscripts - "Getting Information from Pueblo Indians" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "The Good of Society", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Gratifications and Consolation in War Time", 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Heaven", [1914?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - [Hindu Culture] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "The History of the Monroe Doctrine from 1822 to 1861", [ca.1898?]; 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Home Study in Ethnology", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - Hopi Journal by Alexander M. Stephen (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        -See Ser.III, Mss. - Stephen's Hopi Journal
      - Manuscripts - "How Civilization Might Jump", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Humiliation in Crisis Ceremonialism", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "The Imaginary Mistress", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        photocopy
      - Manuscripts - "In New York State", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "In Terms of Crisis", [1917] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "In Terms of Crisis" - Correspondence, 1917-20 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Hackett, Francis (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Hand, Learned (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Smith, T.R. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Toksvig, Signe K. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "In the Beginning of Society", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "In the Nursery - Militarism or Pacifism?", [1915] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "In the Southwest", 14.0 folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #1. "The Accident of the Forester", [ca. 1919]; 20.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
          Includes letter by T. R. Smith.
        - Folder #2. "From Paharito Ranch to Taos and Back", [ca. 1919]; 9.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #3. "Pedro Baca and I Go Visiting", [ca. 1919]; 14.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #4. "The Governor of Zuni", [ca. 1919]; 9.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #5. "In the Room Below", [ca. 1919]; 18.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #6. "The Price of Fear at Zuni", 1921; 19.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
          Includes letter from T. R. Smith.
        - Folder #7. "The Dance North of Houck's Tanks", [ca. 1919]; 12.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #8. "Where the Chief Lives", [ca. 1919]; 18.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #9. "Laguna Lodging Houses", [ca. 1919]; 37.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #10. "How My Head was Washed at Sichumovi", 1920; 14.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
          Includes two letters from T. R. Smith.
        - Folder #11. "Third Degree at Lamy", [ca.1919]; 11.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #12. "The Hotavilla Revival", [ca.1919]; 17.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #13. "Melika", [ca.1919]; 8.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #14. "We Attend the Night Chant", [ca.1919]; 15.0 p (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Indians Ku-Klux-Klanned", [ca.1920] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "International Representation", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Interpreting Ceremonialism", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - [An Island Bewitched] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - La Farge, C. Grant (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
          -See also Ser.I, Day, Clarence, 23 Feb. 1914
        - Folders #1-3, 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
        - Folder #4, 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "It Costs", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Japan and Preparedness", [ca.1917] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 3)
      - Manuscripts - "Journal of a Feminist, 1913-1914", n.d.; 10 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Journal of a Pacifist", n.d.; 5 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - Laws of Imitation - Correspondence Henry Holt and Co., 1902-20 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "The Legal Mind", [1915] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Links Between Religion and Morality in Early Culture", [1914] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
        -See also Ser.I, Goddard, P.E., 29 June 1914
      - Manuscripts - "Little Essays in Lifting Taboo", [ca.1906?]; 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Marriage, A New Life", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Marriage and Parenthood - a Distinction", 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
        - The Atlantic Monthly (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Masks in the Southwest of the United States" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
        -See Ser.IV, Mexico - Notes, 1929-30; 1932
      - Manuscripts - "The Mass of the Cock in Ihuatzia, Michoacan", [ca.1932] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Meetings", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - [Mexican Riddles], n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "Mistaking a Lady", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - Mitla: Town of Souls - Correspondence Redfield, Robert, 1935-36 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - "The Near Conjugal", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 4)
      - Manuscripts - [Negro Folklore], n.d.; 5 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "New England Folklore", 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        original microfilmed then discarded; see Manuscripts Librarian for film
      - Manuscripts - "Note on Parallels Between the Cora-Huichol and the Pueblos", [1933] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Nursery and Savagery" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Nursery Bug-A-Boos", [1912]-15 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        - The Independent (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Nursery Taboos", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - The Old-Fashioned Woman - Reviews and Correspondence, 1913-16 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Old Signs in Alabama" by N.F. Woodall, [1930] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        -See Ser.III, Mss. - "Spirituals in Alabama" by Clemmie S. Terrell
      - Manuscripts - "On Certain Phases of Poor-Relief in the City of New York", [ca.1898]; 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "On Dueling and Reprisals" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "On the Loose" - Reviews and Corr., 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "On the Training of the Will", [ca.1898] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Pacifist Snobbishness", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        - Dell, Floyd (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - [Pawnee Indians], [1925] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - [Patriotism], n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - Peguche: a Study of Andean Indians - Correspondence (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        -See Ser.X, Corr. - Redfield, Robert
        -See Ser.X, Corr. - Reichard, Gladys A.
        -See Ser.X, Publications
      - Manuscripts - Peguche: a Study of Andean Indians - Reviews, 1945-47 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "A Plan for a National Employment Agency", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - [Plates and Figures to Unidentified Works] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Pleas for Marriage", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "A Poor Boy", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Portrait of an Adventurer", 1919; 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        re: Clarence Day
        - Day, Peggy (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        - The New Republic (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        - The New Yorker (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Primitive Custom in Modern Culture", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "The Procession of St. Sebastian and the Virgin at Santa Maria Azompa", [ca.1932] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Property and Habit", 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        - Seager, Henry N. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Provenience of Certain Negro Folk-Tales", n.d.; 6 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Proverbs from Barbados and the Bahamas", [1930?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Psychological Aspects of the Taboos and Ceremonials of Pregnancy" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Pueblo Indian Parallels: an Ethnologic Study in Behaviors and Psychology", [ca. 1920] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "The Puppet of the Ceremonial", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Religion of Middle Age", [1917?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        -See Ser.III, Mss. - Review of H.G. Wells' God the Invisible King
      - Manuscripts - Religious Chastity - Reviews and Corr., 1912-14 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Religious Folk Dances of Mexico", 1929 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "The Reluctant Bridegroom", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - Review of N.W. Thomas' Kinship Organization and Group Marriage in Australia, [1907?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - Review of H.G. Wells' God the Invisible King, [1917?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "Ring Games and Jingles in Barbados", [1930?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
      - Manuscripts - "A Romantic in Bengal and in New York", [1925?]; 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        -See also Ser.IV, Hindu - Notes, [1923]
      - Manuscripts - "A Romantic in Bengal and in New York", 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 5)
        page proofs
      - Manuscripts - "Saints of Uruápan", [ca. 1932] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Selfishness", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "The Sentimentalists", [ca. 1913?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Sentimentality and Ceremonialism" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Sex and the Elders", [1915] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Sexual Taboo", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Shall We Send Our Daughters to College?" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Miller, Alice Duer (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Sincerity in Love Affairs", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - Social Freedom - Correspondence, 1915-16 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - Social Freedom - Reviews and Critiques, 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - Social Rule - Reviews and accounts, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Social Solidarity", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spanish Elements in the Kachina Cult of the Pueblos", 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spanish Elements in the Kachina Cult of the Pueblos" - Correspondence, 1928-29 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Benedict, Ruth (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Bunzel, Ruth L. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Espinosa, Aurelio M. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Hodge, F.W. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Kroeber, [Alfred L.] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - La Farge, Oliver (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Wissler, Clark (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spanish Elements in the Kachina Cult of the Pueblos" - Notes, [ca. 1930] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spanish Influence in Pueblo Indian Folktales", [ca. 1925?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spanish Influences in Pueblo Indian Folktales" - Cover, [ca. 1925?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - "Spirituals in Alabama" by Clemmie S. Terrell, [1930] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - Alexander M. Stephen's Hopi Journal, [ca. 1936] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        proofs
        -See also Oversized